Guide to the Roundell Tristram Toke diaries and photographs from military service in China and Japan, 1900-1907 RL.11647
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1900-1907; 145 photographs 2 boxes
  - Noe San / Sachio San / Cap. Somerville, circa 1905-1907; 4 1/8 x 3 1/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0069)
    Noe 和 Sachio 两位小姐和萨默维尔上校
    ノエさん、幸夫さん、ソマーヴィル大佐
    The two women appear to be a young girl and mother. As Sachio is usually a man's name, perhaps the original name is Sachiko. The man is John A.C. Somerville, British military attaché.
  - Noe San / Sachio San / Somerville, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0070)
  - Mt. Asama volcano [Honshū], circa 1905-1907; 2 7/8 x 4 1/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0071)
    浅間山火山 [本州]
    浅間山火山（本州）
  - Garden at hot bath, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0072)
    温泉花园
    温泉花園
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 4 1/8 x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0073)
    Noe Yabuki
    Noe Yabuki 小姐
  - Chyō San / Ō Arai, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0074)
    Chyō 小姐 / 新居町
    Chyō お嬢さん / 新居町
    Female child
    女孩
  - Chyō San, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0075)
    Chyō 小姐
    Chyō お嬢さん
  - Chyō San, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0076)
  - Chyō San, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0077)
  - Sachio and Noe Yabuki, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0078)
    Sachio 和 Noe 小姐
    幸夫とノエさん
    The two women appear to be a young girl and mother. As Sachio is usually a man's name, perhaps the original name is Sachiko.
  - Noe San / Sachio San, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0079)
    Noe小姐和 Sachio小姐
    ノエさん、幸夫さん（小姐はお嬢さんという意味ですが？？）
  - O Noe San, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0080)
    Noe小姐
    Noe お嬢さん
  - Japanese hand grenade, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0081)
    日式手榴弹
    日本式手榴弾
  - Kama Kura [Japan], circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0082)
    鎌倉市
    View of seaside town.
    海边城市
  - Penang, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0083)
    槟城
    ペナン
  - Singapore harbour, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0084)
    新加坡港口
    シンガポール湾口
  - View from P. & O. anchorage Singapore, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0085)
    P&O游船停靠处风景，新加坡
    P&O遊覧船停泊時の風景、昭南（シンガポール旧名）
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0086)
    Iris garden view.
    Horikiri is a well-known iris garden in Tokyo.
  - Hori Kiri, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0087)
  - Iris garden, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0088)
  - Iris garden, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0089)
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 2 1/2 x 3 1/2 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0090)
    Unidentified Western female child in a garden, sitting in a toy wagon with dog.
    坐在童车里的西洋女孩和一旁的小狗
  - Russian prisoners of war camp, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0091)
    俄国战俘营
    ロシア捕虜営（捕虜収容所）
    Probably Narashino, where other photographs were taken. Narashino (習志野市 Narashino-shi) is a city located in Chiba Prefecture, Japan. It was the site of a prisoner of war camp built during the Russo-Japanese War.
  - Russian prisoners, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0092)
    俄国战俘
    ロシア捕虜
  - Russian prisoner, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0093)
  - Russian prisoner, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0094)
  - Russian prisoners of war camp, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0095)
    ロシア捕虜営
  - Russian prisoners of war camp, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0096)
  - Russian prisoners at Narashino, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0097)
    習志野市的俄国战俘
    習志野市のロシア捕虜
    Narashino (習志野市 Narashino-shi) is a city located in Chiba Prefecture, Japan. It was the site of a prisoner of war camp built during the Russo-Japanese War.
  - Russian prisoners, circa 1905-1907; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0098)
  - Russian prisoners of war camp, Japan, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0099)
    俄国战俘营，日本
    ロシア捕虜営、日本
  - Russian prisoners at Narashino, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0100)
    習志野市的俄国战俘营
  - Russian prisoners at Narashino, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0101)
  - No known title, circa 1905-1907; 3x4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0102)
    Russian prisoners at Narashino.
  - Chinese children Wei-Hai-Wei, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0103)
    中国儿童，威海卫
    中国児童、威海衛
    Weihaiwei, or Weihai, as it is now known, is a seaport city in northeastern China, Shandong Province.
  - Small Manchu girl, circa 1905; 4x3 inches (Box 3, Print RL-11647-P-0104)
    满族小姑娘
    満州族の乙女
  - Larger photographic prints, circa 1900-1901; 40 photographs 1 box (Box 4)
    Taken in China, these unmounted albumen photographs show scenes associated with the Boxer Rebellion and its aftermath. The prints are larger than the other photographs in the collection.